The Agecroft Collection
The Agecroft Collection
- Documents relating to the Daunteseys of Agecroft, 1573-1777; 84 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/3
  Sir Robert Langley died in 1560, the last of the male line in possession of Agecroft Hall. The following year his daughter and heiress Anne married William Dauntesey of West Lavington co Wilts, son of Richard Dauntesey Gentleman-Usher to Queen Katherine Howard. William's inquisition post mortem records that he died seised of the manors of Prestwich, Pendlebury, and Agecroft, and messuages and lands there and in Alkrington, Tetlow, Oldham, Crompton and Manchester.
  - Copy of a commission to examine witnesses on behalf of William Dauntesey vs Richard Holland and others, 10 Jun 1573; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 140; GB/418/Agecroft/3/1
    15 Eliz I
  - Bond to perform covenants from Richard Holland to William Dauntesey, 15 Aug 1573; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 141; GB/418/Agecroft/3/2
  - Acknowledgement by William Dauntesey to Ellin Lees, 20 May 1587; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 142; GB/418/Agecroft/3/3
  - Marriage settlement of William Dauntesey, son and heir apparent of William Dauntesey, and Katherine Crompton, daughter of Laurence Crompton, decd, 1 Aug 1613; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 143; GB/418/Agecroft/3/4
    11 Jas I
  - Fine between Roger Downes and William Dauntesey and his wife Anne, 9 Aug 1613; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 144; GB/418/Agecroft/3/5
    See Agecroft/3/6 (duplicate)
  - Duplicate Fine between Roger Downes and William Dauntesey and his wife Anne, 9 Aug 1613; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 145; GB/418/Agecroft/3/6
    Duplicate of Agecroft/3/5
  - Inquisition after the death of William Dauntesey, [29 Nov 1622]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 146; GB/418/Agecroft/3/7
    20 Jas I
  - Release for the portion of goods left to Katherine, wife of William Dauntessey, by her late father, 30 Oct 1624; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 147; GB/418/Agecroft/3/8
    From William Dauntesey, esq, to Laurence Crompton, his brother in law
    Paper - torn along fold
  - General livery of the lands of William Dauntesey, [20 Mar 1625]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 148; GB/418/Agecroft/3/9
    Part of great seal remains - handle with care.
    [20 Mar 1624/5], 22 Jas I
  - Fine levied on the manor of Pendlebury etc between James Crompton, gent, plaintiff, and William Dauntesey, esq, deforciant, 29 Aug 1625; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 149; GB/418/Agecroft/3/10
    1 Chas I
    Duplicate at Agecroft/3/11
  - Duplicate Fine levied on the manor of Pendlebury etc between James Crompton, gent, plaintiff, and William Dauntesey, esq, deforciant, 29 Aug 1625; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 150; GB/418/Agecroft/3/11
    Duplicate of Agecroft/3/10
  - Recovery of the Manor of Pendlebury, 29 Aug 1625; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 151; GB/418/Agecroft/3/12
  - Settlement by William Dauntesey of Agecroft Hall and messuages, lands etc in Pendlebury, Prestwich etc, 6 May 1634; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 152; GB/418/Agecroft/3/13
  - Probate of the will of William Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, 31 Mar 1637; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 153; GB/418/Agecroft/3/14
    Will dated 2 Jan 1636/7
  - Grant to Katherine Dauntsey, widow, of part of the lands etc of William Dauntesey, esq, decd, 1 Jul 1637; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 154; GB/418/Agecroft/3/15
  - Grant to Katherine Dauntsey of Agecroft, widow, of the wardship and marriage of William Dauntesey, son and heir of William Dauntesey, decd, 3 Jul 1637; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 155; GB/418/Agecroft/3/16
  - Bond from Leonard Egerton to John Dauntesey, 24 Mar 1670; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 156; GB/418/Agecroft/3/17
    24 Mar 1669/70
  - Fine between John Dauntesey, esq, plaintiff, and Leonard Egerton, esq, and Mary his wife, deforciants, 3 Apr 1671; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 157; GB/418/Agecroft/3/18
    Of 1 cottage, 1 garden, 12 acres of land, 6 acres of meadow, and 12 acres of pasture with appurtenances in Pendlebury, which the said Leonard and Mary acknowledge to be the right of the said John as those which the said John has of the gift of the said Leonard and Mary. For this acknowledgement John has given Leonard and Mary £133 6s 8d.
    23 Chas II
  - Copy of settlement of Agecroft Hall by John Dauntesey, 15 Feb 1693; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 159; GB/418/Agecroft/3/19
    15 Feb 1692/3
  - Lease of parcels of Agecroft Hall, 26 Jun 1694; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bundle no 1 no 160; GB/418/Agecroft/3/20
    From James Taylor of Gorton and others (trustees of John Dauntesey of Agecroft, decd) to Robert Holden of Pendleton co Lancs, whitster
  - Assignment of the personal estate of John Dauntesey, esq, decd, 26 Jun 1694; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 161; GB/418/Agecroft/3/21
    From Christopher, John, Thomas and Byron Dauntesey (4 of the younger sons and executors of the will of John Dauntesey, late of Agecroft, decd) to William Dauntesey (eldest son and heir of the said John Dauntesey, decd).
  - Lease of parcels of Agecroft Hall, 14 Sep 1695; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 162; GB/418/Agecroft/3/22
  - Lease for 6 months from Christopher Dauntesey to James Taylor, 1 Aug 1696; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 163; GB/418/Agecroft/3/23
    Insect damage on one of the tags
  - Deed to lead the uses of a fine of Agecroft Hall and messuages in Manchester, Prestwich, Eccles etc, 3 Aug 1696; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 164; GB/418/Agecroft/3/24
    Between Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, co Lancs, gent (now eldest son and heir of John Dauntesey late of Agecroft, esq, decd), James Taylor of Gorton, John Waite of Manchester co Lancs, gent, and John Wardle of Manchester, gent.
    Insect damage
  - Duplicate deed to lead the uses of a fine of Agecroft Hall and messuages in Manchester, Prestwich, Eccles etc, 3 Aug 1696; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 165; GB/418/Agecroft/3/25
    Between Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, co Lancs, gent (now eldest son and heir of John Dauntesey late of Agecroft, esq, decd), James Taylor of Gorton John Waite of Manchester co Lancs, gent, and John Wardle of Manchester, gent.
  - Mortgage of parcels of Agecroft Hall for £200, 22 Sep 1696; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 166; GB/418/Agecroft/3/26
    From Christopher Dauntesey,gent, to Thomas Mynshull the younger, gent.
  - Articles of agreement made previous to the marriage of Christopher Dauntesey, esq, with Mary, daughter of Sir Edward Chisnall of Chisnall, kt, 18 Jan 1697; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 167; GB/418/Agecroft/3/27
    18 Jan 1696/7
  - Mortgage of parcels of Agecroft Hall from Christopher Dauntesey to Sir Edward Chisnall for £700, 31 Oct 1698; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 168; GB/418/Agecroft/3/28
  - Releases from Thomas Dauntesey to Christopher Dauntesey, 5 Nov 1698; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 169; GB/418/Agecroft/3/29
  - Release from Elizabeth Dauntesey to Christopher Dauntesey, 2 Nov 1700; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 170; GB/418/Agecroft/3/30
  - Deed to suffer a recovery of all those messuages etc now or late in the several tenures of Henry Dickanson, 10 Jul 1703; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 171; GB/418/Agecroft/3/31
  - Release from Trustees of Christopher Dauntesey, esq, and his heir for ever, of all their right in Agecroft Hall, 23 Jul 1703; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 172; GB/418/Agecroft/3/32
  - Lease for 6 months of Agecroft Hall, 28 Jul 1703; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 173; GB/418/Agecroft/3/33
    From Christopher Dauntesey to John W[?a]ite of Manchester, gent
  - Deed to suffer a recovery of Agecroft Hall, 30 Jul 1703; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 174; GB/418/Agecroft/3/34
    Between Christopher Dauntesey (now eldest son and heir of John Dauntesey) and John Waite of Manchester, gent
  - Appointment by James, Earl of Derby of Christopher Dauntesey to be Captain in Regiment of Foot, 4 Oct 1703; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 175; GB/418/Agecroft/3/35
  - Conveyance of 1 acre, 1 rood of land, 4 Jan 1704; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 176; GB/418/Agecroft/3/36
    From Christopher Dauntesey to Henry Greenhalgh
    4 Jan 1703/4
  - Copy of marriage settlement between Christopher Dauntesey and Mary Chisnall, 8 Mar 17034; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 177; GB/418/Agecroft/3/37
    8 Mar 1703/4
  - Conveyance from Sir Edward Chisnall and others to Thomas Bradshaw, 18 Apr 1704; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 178; GB/418/Agecroft/3/38
    Sir Edward Chisnall acting for Christopher Dauntesey.
  - Agreement between Christopher Dauntesey and Daniel Gaskell, 20 Jun 1704; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 179; GB/418/Agecroft/3/39
  - Conveyance from Sir Edward Chisnall and others to Robert Holden, 21 Jun 1704; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 180; GB/418/Agecroft/3/40
  - Memorandum concerning a close sold by Christopher Dauntesey to Henry Greenhalgh, 11 Sep 1705; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 181; GB/418/Agecroft/3/41
    Restrictions on use of riverside land leased to Henry Greenhalgh by deed no 176
  - Grant from Queen Anne to Christopher Dauntesey esq of the office of Sheriff of the county of Lancaster, 13 Dec 1705; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 182; GB/418/Agecroft/3/42
    4 Anne
    Seal intact
  - Appointment by Christopher Dauntesey, esq, High Sheriff of the county of Lancaster, of Ralph Ashton of Preston, gent, as his clerk or steward of his county court, 28 Dec 1705; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 183; GB/418/Agecroft/3/43
  - Assignment of Parke House, 10 Feb 1707; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 184; GB/418/Agecroft/3/44
    From Christopher Dauntesey to Thomas Mosse and William Shrigley
    10 Feb 1706/7
  - Assignment from Christopher Dauntesey to Robert Holden, 1 Jul 1707; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 185; GB/418/Agecroft/3/45
  - Draft of Assignment from Christopher Dauntesey to Christopher Rode and others, 23 Jul 1707; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 186; GB/418/Agecroft/3/46
    6 Anne
  - Bond from Edward Dauntesey to Thomas Holland, 15 Oct 1720; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 2 bdl 2 no 187; GB/418/Agecroft/3/47
  - Lease for a year of Agecroft Hall and the demesne lands thereto belonging and messuages etc in Pendlebury, Pendleton, Swinton, Worsley, Prestwich, Manchester and Eccles, 4 Aug 1721; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 188; GB/418/Agecroft/3/48
    From Edward Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Byron Starkey of Preston and Nicholas Woosey, of the same, gents
  - Deed to suffer a recovery of Agecroft Hall and the demesne lands thereto belonging, and messuages etc in Pendlebury, Pendleton, Swinton, Worsley, Prestwich, Manchester and Eccles, 5 Aug 1721; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 189; GB/418/Agecroft/3/49
    Made between Edward Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, Byron Starkey and Nicholas Woosey of Preston, William Langton of Preston, and George Curbisley of Manchester, gents.
  - Assignment of right in Agecroft Hall etc and messuages in Pendlebury, Pendleton, Swinton etc, 23 Oct 1727; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 190; GB/418/Agecroft/3/50
    From William Ashton of Prestwich, co Lancs, clerk, and others (trustees for Christopher Dauntesey late of Pendlebury, co Lancs, esq, decd) to William Chisenhall of Chisenhall, co Lancs (eldest son and heir of Sir Edward Chisenhall, co Lancs, decd) and Byron Starkey of Preston co Lancs, gent (trustees appointed by the Court of Chancery).
  - Mortgage of the Bury House and certain closes etc, 22 Nov 1727; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 191; GB/418/Agecroft/3/51
    From William Chisenhall of Chisenhall co Lancs, esq, Byron Starkey of Preston, co Lancs, gent, and Christopher Dauntesey of Manchester, gent, to Miles Neild of Manchester, merchant, for £333 6s 8d.
  - Release for Christopher Dauntesey's share of the sum of £1,000 charged on Agecroft Hall etc by his late father Christopher Dauntesey of Pendlebury esq, decd, 22 Nov 1727; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 192; GB/418/Agecroft/3/52
    From Christopher Dauntesey of Manchester, gent, to William Chisenhall of Chisenhall, esq, and Byron Starkey of Preston, gent, trustees.
  - Mortgage of parcels of the demesne lands of Agecroft, 16 Jun 1729; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 193; GB/418/Agecroft/3/53
    From William Chisenhall of Chisenhall, esq, and Byron Starkey of Preston, gent, to Miles Neild of Manchester, merchant, for £333 6s 8d to enable the said William Chisenhall etc to pay to John Jesson of Salford, chapman, administrator of Elizabeth his wife (one of the daughters of Christopher Dauntesey late of Pendlebury, esq, and Mary his wife, both decd) the portion of the said Elizabeth.
  - Articles of agreement relating to the settlement of Agecroft Estate etc, 28 Feb 1733; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 194; GB/418/Agecroft/3/54
    Between Edward Dauntesey of Agecroft within Pendlebury, co Lancs, esq, and Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft aforesaid, gentleman (younger and only brother of the said Edward Dauntesey).
    28 Feb 1732/3, 6 Geo II
  - Lease for 6 months of Agecroft Hall and the demesne lands thereto belonging and messuages etc in Pendlebury, Swinton, Worsley, Prestwich, Manchester and Eccles co Lancs, 19 Apr 1733; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 195; GB/418/Agecroft/3/55
    From Edward Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft aforesaid, gent (younger and only brother and heir presumptive of the said Edward Dauntesey).
  - Conveyance of Agecroft Hall and the demesne lands thereto belonging and messuages etc in Pendlebury, Swinton, Worsley, Prestwich, Mancheseter and Eccles co Lancs, 20 Apr 1733; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 196; GB/418/Agecroft/3/56
    From Edward Dauntesey of Agecroft esq to Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft gent (younger and only brother and heir presumptive of the said Edward Dauntesey) his heirs and assigns for ever.
  - Assignment, 7 May 1735; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 197; GB/418/Agecroft/3/57
    From Mr Robert Plumbe of Liverpool, and Jane his wife (youngest daughter of Christopher Dauntesey esq, decd) to Mr Robert Billinge for Mr Christopher Dauntesey, of all their claim to a share of £1,000 charged on the Agecroft Estate by the said Christopher Dauntesey, esq, decd.
  - Lease for a year of Agecroft Hall and the demesne lands thereto belonging and messuages etc in Pendlebury, Pendleton, Swinton, Worsley, Prestwich and Eccles co Lancs, 29 May 1735; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 198; GB/418/Agecroft/3/58
    From Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, gent to Richard Bolton of Prestbury co Chester, clerk, and Robert Lawe of Charnock co Lancs, gent.
    Duplicate at Agecroft/3/59
  - Duplicate lease for a year of Agecroft Hall and the demesne lands thereto belonging and messuages etc in Pendlebury, Pendleton, Swinton, Worsley, Prestwich and Eccles co Lancs, 29 May 1735; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 199; GB/418/Agecroft/3/59
    From Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, gent, to Richard Bolton of Prestbury co Chester, clerk, and Robert Lawe of Charnock co Lancs, gent.
    Duplicate of Agecroft/3/58
  - Settlement of Agecroft Hall and the demesne lands thereto belonging, and messages etc in Pendlebury, Pendleton, Swinton, etc, 30 May 1735; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 200; GB/418/Agecroft/3/60
    Between Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft within Pendlebury, co Lancs, gent, and Elizabeth his wife, Robert Billinge of Eccleston near Croston co Lancs, gent (father of the said Elizabeth) Richard Bolton of Prestbury, co Chester, clerk and Robert Lawe of Charnock, co Lancs, gent.
    Duplicate at Agecroft/3/61
  - Duplicate Settlement of Agecroft Hall and the demesne lands thereto belonging, and messages etc in Pendlebury, Pendleton, Swinton, etc, 30 May 1735; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 201; GB/418/Agecroft/3/61
    Between Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft within Pendlebury co Lancs, gent, and Elizabeth his wife, Robert Billinge of Eccleston near Croston co Lancs, gent (father of the said Elizabeth) Richard Bolton of Prestbury co Chester, clerk and Robert Lawe of Charnock co Lancs, gent.
    Duplicate of Agecroft/3/60
  - Mortgage of Agecroft Hall and the demesne lands thereto belonging and messuages etc in Pendlebury, Pendleton, Swinton, Worsley, Prestwich and Eccles co Lancs, 10 Aug 1744; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 202; GB/418/Agecroft/3/62
    From Christopher Dauntesey of Wigan co Lancs, gent, to Robert Billinge of Eccleston, near Croston co Lancs, gent, to indemnify him from certain bonds etc.
    Duplicate at Agecroft/3/63
  - Duplicate mortgage of Agecroft Hall and the demesne lands thereto belonging and messuages etc in Pendlebury, Pendleton, Swinton, Worsley, Prestwich and Eccles co Lancs, 10 Aug 1744; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 203; GB/418/Agecroft/3/63
    Duplicate of Agecroft/3/62
  - Probate of the will of Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft in Pendlebury co Lancs, gent, 28 Oct 1748; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 204; GB/418/Agecroft/3/64
    Will dated 22 Dec 1747
  - Lease for a year of Agecroft Hall and Park House in Pendlebury, co Lancs and messuages, lands etc in Prestwich, Pendleton and Manchester, 21 Feb 1757; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 205; GB/418/Agecroft/3/65
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft esq (now a student in St Peter's College, Cambridge) to Henry Smith of Preston co Lancs, gent.
  - Deed to suffer a recovery of Agecroft Hall and Park House etc to the use of the Trustees for a certain term and afterwards to the use of John Dauntesey, esq, 22 Feb 1757; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 206; GB/418/Agecroft/3/66
  - Recovery - Robert Billinge and John Cooper, Henry Smith, John Dauntesey, 12 Mar 1757; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 207; GB/418/Agecroft/3/67
    30 Geo II
  - Lease for a year of Agecroft Hall and Park House in Pendlebury, co Lancs and messuages, lands etc in Prestwich, Pendleton and Manchester, 6 Feb 1758; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 208; GB/418/Agecroft/3/68
  - Mortgage in fee of Agecroft Hall to Mr Cunliffe, 7 Feb 1758; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 209; GB/418/Agecroft/3/69
    And transfer of two several terms of 500 years and 1,000 years to trustees for the use of the mortgages to secure 2,000th and interest.
  - Lease for a year of Agecroft Hall and Park House in Pendlebury, co Lancs and messuages, lands etc in Prestwich, Pendleton and Manchester, 23 Aug 1759; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 210; GB/418/Agecroft/3/70
    From Sir Ellis Cunliffe, Bart Robert Cunliffe, esq, and John Dauntesey, esq, to James Worthington of Preston, esq.
  - Mortgage of Agecroft Hall and Park House in Pendlebury, co Lancs and messuages, lands etc in Prestwich, Pendleton and Manchester, 24 Aug 1759; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 211; GB/418/Agecroft/3/71
    From Sir Ellis Cunliffe, Bart Robert Cunliffe, esq, and John Dauntesey, esq, to James Worthington of Preston, esq, for £2,000.
  - Assignment of two terms to attend inheritance - Agecroft Hall, 25 Aug 1759; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 212; GB/418/Agecroft/3/72
  - Mr John Dauntesey's deed of covenants to procure a term of 500 years to be assigned in trust to attend inheritance, 25 Aug 1759; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 213; GB/418/Agecroft/3/73
  - Deacons Orders by Edmund, Bishop of Chester, to John Dauntesey, BA St Peter's College, Cambridge, 12 Oct 1760; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 214; GB/418/Agecroft/3/74
  - Licence from Edmund, Bishop of Chester, to John Dauntesey BA, to perform the office of curate in the parish and parish church of Ashton upon Mersey, co Ches, 13 Oct 1760; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 215; GB/418/Agecroft/3/75
  - Priests orders by Edmund, Bishop of Chester, to John Dauntesey, BA of St Peter's College, Cambridge, 5 Jul 1761; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 216; GB/418/Agecroft/3/76
  - Bond concerning the cutting of trees on Agecroft Estate, 2 Dec 1761; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 217; GB/418/Agecroft/3/77
    From James Ffildes of Pendlebury co Lancs, yeo, and Thomas Ffildes of the same place, wheelwright, to the Rev John Dauntesey of Manchester, clerk.
  - Articles between the Rev Mr John Dauntesey and Rev Mr John Foster, 18 Oct 1763; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 218; GB/418/Agecroft/3/78
  - Lease for a year of Slater's Tenement in Pendleton, co Lancs, 28 Jul 1780; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 219; GB/418/Agecroft/3/79
    From John Dauntesey, clerk, to William Calvert of Whitlane in Pendleton, gent, and Margaret Holland of Pendleton, spinster.
  - Conveyance of Slater's Tenement in Pendleton, co Lancs, nd [18th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 220; GB/418/Agecroft/3/80
    From Rev John Dauntesey of 'Edgecroft' co Lancs, clerk, to William Calvert of Whitlane in Pendleton, gent, and Margaret Holland of Pendleton, spinster, their heirs and assigns for ever.
  - Administration with the will of Catherine Dauntesey late of Agecroft co Lancs, spinster, decd, 7 Nov 1805; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 221; GB/418/Agecroft/3/81
    Granted to Rev John Dauntesey, only brother and sole next of kin of the said deceased. Will dated 8 Aug 1804.
  - Copy of the will of Rev J Dauntesey of Agecroft, co Lancs, 10 Oct 1811; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 3 no 222; GB/418/Agecroft/3/82
  - Copy bill: Fields and others v Hanson, 28 Jan 1777; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 266; GB/418/Agecroft/3/83
  - Dauntesey v Hanson: close copy answer sworn, 3 Nov 1777; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 267; GB/418/Agecroft/3/84
- Documents relating to Pendlebury, Pendleton, Prestwich etc, 1631-1787; 32 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/4
  - Lease of certain tithes in Pendleton, co Lancs, 8 Apr 1631; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 223; GB/418/Agecroft/4/1
    From Christopher Anderton of Lostock co Lancs, esq, to William Dauntesey of Agecroft co Lancs, gent.
    Term: 21 years
    7 Chas I
  - Lease of closes in Pendleton, co Lancs, 10 Aug 1633; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 nos 224 & 225; GB/418/Agecroft/4/2
    From William Dauntesey of Agecroft co Lancs, esq, to Anne Bradshawe, of Newhall in Pendleton, widow.
    Term: 3 lives
  - Lease of two closes in Pendleton, co Lancs, 14 Dec 1635; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 226; GB/418/Agecroft/4/3
    From William Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Alice Higginson of Pendleton, widow.
    11 Chas
  - Lease of a parcel of land in Manchester, co Lancs, 24 Nov 1688; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 227; GB/418/Agecroft/4/4
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Robert Hardy of Manchester, joiner.
  - Lease of a messuage in Manchester, co Lancs, 5 Mar 1670; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 228; GB/418/Agecroft/4/5
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Henry Dickinson of Manchester, linen draper.
    5 Mar 1669/70
  - Lease of a messuage etc in Pendleton, co Lancs, 20 Sep 1673; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 nos 229 & 230; GB/418/Agecroft/4/6
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Robert Houlden of Little Bolton within Pendleton.
    25 Chas II
  - Lease of a cottage etc in Agecroft co Lancs, 8 Dec 1683; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 231; GB/418/Agecroft/4/7
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Hugh Berry of Agecroft, husbandman.
    Term: 50 years if the said Hugh Berry and Elizabeth his wife so long live
    35 Chas II
  - Lease of a messuage etc in Prestwich, co Lancs, 8 Dec 1683; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 232; GB/418/Agecroft/4/8